Guide to the John McComb Architectural Drawings Collection 1766-1829 PR 40
New-York Historical Society
- Sketch Designs for hanging candelabras: attributed (Box McComb Box 18, Item 357)
- Sketch Drawing of a door with transom and a ceiling rosette: attributed (Box McComb Box 18, Item 366)
- Sketch, ornament [Lyre, sunburst, olive branch, cloud] (Box McComb Box 16, Item 300)
- Sketches, Vitruvius Britannicus, [1809] (Box McComb box 1, Item 23)
- St. John's Chapel, 1807 (Box McComb box 3, Item 50)
- St. John's Chapel, 1803 (Box Drawer 7, Item 53)
- St. John's Chapel [attrib.], 1807 (Box McComb box 3, Item 52)
- St. John's Chapel [attrib], 1807 (Box McComb box 3, Item 51)
- St. John's Chapel, attributed graphite, LC: [St. John's Chapel?] (Box McComb Box 8, Item 126)
- St. Johns Church Ink, LC-LR: "First Story windows for St. Johns Church" (Box McComb Box 8, Item 125)
- St. Johns Church [Canandaigua] [Gothic] graphite, MC-MR: "St. Johns church" (Box McComb Box 16, Item 302)
- St. Paul's Chapel ink, LC-LR: "Peir & Urn disigned for S.t Pauls church yard -" (Box McComb Box 16, Item 318)
- St. Paul's Chapel, monument, sculptural tablet Verso, ink, UL: "Monument" (Box McComb box 4, Item 67)
- St. Paul's steeple St. Paul's Steeple. Ink MC, 1794 ink MC (Box McComb box 3, Item 61)
- St. Paul's steeple, [1794] (Box McComb box 3, Item 62)
- St. Paul's steeple: attrib. pencil, ML: "from ground 143 feet" (Box McComb Box 21, Item 453 verso)
- St. Peter's Church Ink, LC: "Front-View of St. Peters Church with the intended Steeple" (Box McComb box 4, Item 70)
- St. Peter's Church (Box McComb box 4, Item 069 verso)
- Stiles and Beach Farm map (Box McComb Box 5, Item 86)
- Store/house on Water Street (Box McComb box 3, Item 059b verso)
- Stove designed as a fluted column with urn on top: attributed (Box McComb Box 17, Item 331)
- Study for gates and piers: attrib. (Box McComb Box 16, Item 308 recto)
- Study of Egyptian Temple ink, MC: "Egyptian Temple" (Box McComb Box 21, Item 451)
- Study of Pantheon, attrib. pencil, UR-MR: "From the Pantheon" (Box McComb Box 16, Item 307)
- Study of Temple of Vesta, attrib. pencil, UL-UR: "Frieze of the Temple of Vesta" (Box McComb Box 16, Item 305)
- Sugar Refinery, attrib. (Box McComb Box 20, Item 426)
- Summer House [attrib in pencil LL] (Box McComb box 1, Item 14)
- Table Table showing the number of feet vertical to each degree of elevation at 100' feet horizontal. Ink LL to LR. (Box McComb box 2, Item 31)
- The London Lying-in Hospital (Box McComb box 1, Item 025a recto)
- Theater, graphite LL-LR (Box McComb box 4, Item 74)
- Theater, pencil LL-LR (Box McComb box 4, Item A74)
- Town house, unidentified ink, LC: "1st Story" (Box McComb Box 14, Item 239)
- Tract house ink, LC: "Nassau St.", 1825 (Box McComb Box 12, Item 212)
- Tudor window and door openings, attrib. (Box McComb Box 16, Item 306)
- Two story building with tower, unidentified (Box McComb Box 20, Item 425)
- Two-masted square rigger, attrib. (Box McComb Box 16, Item 312 verso)
- Two-masted square rigger, attrib. (Box McComb Box 16, Item 312)
- Urn Urn in niche: attributed (Box McComb Box 17, Item 338 verso)
- Urn (Box McComb Box 17, Item 333)
- Vestibule pilasters, necking Necking at large for pilasters in vestibule (Box McComb box 1, Item 024c)
- Volute ink, UC-UR: "Manner of dicribeing the Elliptical Volute" (Box McComb Box 20, Item 428)
- Volute ink, UL-UR: "P Nicholsons method of describing the Ionic Volute whole Height of Capitals 35M." (Box McComb Box 20, Item 430)
- Volute ink, UL: "Taken fm P. Nicholsons Principals of Architecture" (Box McComb Box 20, Item 431)
- Volute ink, UL-UC: "Method of describing an angular Volute-" (Box McComb Box 20, Item 429)
- Wall Street Presbyterian Church Ink, LC: "Wall Street" (Box McComb Box 10, Item 164)
- Wall Street Presbyterian Church (Box McComb Box 10, Item 167 recto)
- Wall Street Presbyterian Church (Box McComb Box 10, Item 166a)
- Wall Street Presbyterian Church (Box McComb Box 10, Item 166b)
- Wall Street Presbyterian Church, attributed (Box McComb Box 10, Item 168a recto)
- Wall Street Presbyterian Church, attributed, [1823] (Box McComb Box 10, Item 165)
- Wall Street Presbyterian Church, attributed, 1823; April 6: ink, LR (Box McComb Box 10, Item 169)
- Wall Street Presbyterian Church, attributed (Box McComb Box 10, Item 168b verso)
- Wall with Palladian opening, attributed (Box McComb Box 19, Item 394)
- Washington Hall, [1809] (Box McComb box 3, Item 043a)
- Washington Hall Ink, LR: " the Amity to the Merit", 1809; July 4 (Box McComb Box 8, Item 123)
- Washington Hall, 1809; July 4 (Box McComb Box 8, Item 121)
- Washington Hall, 1809, July 4 (Box McComb Box 7, Item 118x recto)
- Washington Hall, 1809, July 4 (Box McComb Box 7, Item 118q)
- Washington Hall, [1809] (Box McComb box 3, Item 043b)
- Washington Hall Ink, UL-UR: "Frame & Sill for the front of the Rear Building at 1/2 Size Frame & Sill for the Front of Washington Hall at 1/2 Size", 1809, July 4 (Box McComb Box 7, Item 118e)
- Washington Hall, 1809; July 4 (Box McComb Box 8, Item 120)
- Washington Hall, 1809, July 4 (Box McComb Box 7, Item 118p)
- Washington Hall Ink, MC: "McCombs Drawings of Washington Hall 1809", 1809, July 4 (Box McComb Box 7, Item 118)
- Washington Hall A design for the front elevation of Washington Hall to be built on Nassau and Spruce Sts.: attributed (Box McComb Box 12, Item 211)
- Washington Hall, 1809, July 4 (Box McComb Box 7, Item 118aa)
- Washington Hall Circular building: unidentified, plan and elevation, 1809, July 4 (Box McComb Box 7, Item 118k verso)
- Washington Hall Ink, LL-LR: "Section of Stairs and Passage", 1809, July 4 (Box McComb Box 7, Item 118j)
- Washington Hall Ink, LC-LR: "Washington Hall on Read Street-", 1809, July 4 (Box McComb Box 7, Item 118l)
- Washington Hall Ink, LC: "as Executed", 1809, July 4 (Box McComb Box 7, Item 118c)
- Washington Hall Ink, UC-UR: "Plan of framing Spring floor of Washington Hall-", 1809; July 4 (Box McComb Box 8, Item 122)
- Washington Hall Ink, LL-LR: "Plan of the first Floor of Washington Hall with the framing of the floor", 1809, July 4 (Box McComb Box 7, Item 118t)
- Washington Hall graphite, ML-MC: "Chimney Top-full Size", 1809, July 4 (Box McComb Box 7, Item 118a 1/2 verso)
- Washington Hall Roof framing plan [attrib.], 1809; July 4 (Box McComb Box 7, Item 118a recto)
- Washington Hall, 1809, July 4 (Box McComb Box 7, Item 118x1/2 verso)
- Washington Hall First and second floor plans, Reade Street portion, 1809, July 4 (Box McComb Box 7, Item 118k recto)
- Washington Hall, 1809, July 4 (Box McComb Box 7, Item 118z recto)
- Washington Hall Ink, LC: "Plan and Section of an Ice Vault for Washington Hall", 1809, July 4 (Box McComb Box 7, Item 118u)
- Washington Hall Entrance design, interior [attrib.], 1809, July 4 (Box McComb Box 7, Item 118)
- Washington Hall Ink, LC: "Sketch of the front of Washington Hall-", 1809, July 4 (Box McComb Box 7, Item 118m)
- Washington Hall, 1809, July 4 (Box McComb Box 7, Item 118h)
- Washington Hall, 1809, July 4 (Box McComb Box 7, Item 118o)
- Washington Hall A design for the front elevation of Washington Hall not adopted [attrib.], [1809] (Box McComb box 6, Item 119)
- Washington Hall Elevations, 1809, July 4 (Box McComb Box 7, Item 118r)
- Washington Hall Ink, LC-LR: "First design for Washington Hall-", 1809, July 4 (Box McComb Box 7, Item 118n)
- Washington Hall Ink, LC: "2c. Story of Washington Hall-", 1809, July 4 (Box McComb Box 7, Item 118s)
- Washington Hall Ink, LL-LR: "Plan, of the Fire place in the N.E. back Room of Washington Hall - with a Section of the flue and Air Chamber", 1809, July 4 (Box McComb Box 7, Item 118i)
- Washington Hall Column and entablature details [attrib.], 1809, July 4 (Box McComb Box 7, Item 118)
- Washington Hall Ink, UL-UC: "Plan and Mouldings for Niche in the Hall-", 1809, July 4 (Box McComb Box 7, Item 118bb)
- Washington Hall, 1809, July 4 (Box McComb Box 7, Item 118v)
- Washington Hall, 1809, July 4 (Box McComb Box 7, Item 118b)
- Washington Hall, [1809] (Box McComb box 6, Item 117)
- Washington Hall, 1809, July 4 (Box McComb Box 7, Item 118w)
- Washington Hall, 1809, July 4 (Box McComb Box 7, Item 118z1/2 verso)
- Washington Hall, 1809, July 4 (Box McComb Box 7, Item 118y)
- Washington Hall Entablature frieze details [attrib.], 1809, July 4 (Box McComb Box 7, Item 118g)
- Washington Hall [attrib in pencil LL] (Box McComb box 1, Item 18)
- Washington Hall [attrib.] (Box McComb box 6, Item 116)
- Washington Hall, attributed ink, UL-UC: "Hall - 87' - x 56'-" (Box McComb Box 19, Item 392)
- Washington Hall, Lydig's Lot, plan of, [1809] (Box McComb box 3, Item 043c)
- Waterworks, attrib. (Box McComb Box 16, Item 324)
- Weathervane ornament (Box McComb box 3, Item 058b verso)
- Wharf, attributed ink, LC: "Plan showing the 1st 2d 3d & 4th course of Timbers" (Box McComb Box 12, Item 210)
- Wharf, attributed (Box McComb Box 12, Item 201)
- Window sill and sash, attrib. (Box McComb Box 15, Item 266 verso)
- Woman, unidentified (Box McComb box 2, Item 38)